certiport.com 2002-02-03

# Certiport > Privacy

Certiport, Inc. (“Certiport”) adheres to standards that allow us to protect as confidential all personal information collected during interaction with electronic applications and Web sites operated by or in behalf of Certiport. To protect your privacy, Certiport utilizes technology and policy in accordance with worldwide practices for customer privacy and data protection.

Select your communication options from Certiport and its partners.

**Collecting Personal Information**  
At various times when interacting with applications or Web sites you may be asked to electronically register or otherwise enter personally identifying information. Generally this information is requested when you are asked to register before taking an assessment test or certification exam, joining a limited-access site, applying for programs, making an electronic purchase, ordering e-mail newsletters, or subscribing for related services or promotions. Personally identifiable information collected by Certiport is used to deliver those products and services you request as required and is never gathered without your knowledge.

**Use of your Personal Information**  
Certiport uses your personal information for five primary purposes:

  1. To identify you as the individual who has taken an exam, to deliver your certification status and certificate, and to allow you to manage your credentials online
  2. To facilitate future interactions with the site or application
  3. To help us create content that is most relevant to you
  4. To alert you to product upgrades, special offers or promotions, and information updates and services from Certiport and its partners
  5. To provide feedback to the various companies or organizations that sponsor the certification you may be pursuing

We occasionally hire other companies to provide services on our behalf, including shipping, online shopping services, survey management, etc. We provide those companies only with the information they need to deliver that service. They are prohibited from using that information for other purposes.

Certiport will disclose your personal information, without notice, if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is required to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Certiport, its site, or business partners; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Certiport and its Web sites, applications or intellectual property; and (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Certiport, its Web sites, or the public.

**Control of your Personal Information**  
You will be able to select the types of electronic communication you wish to receive from Certiport or its business partners by interacting with an opt-out application hosted on www.certiport.com. This application allows you to enter your e-mail address and elect which types of communication you prefer not to receive. These elections will remain in place and be honored by Certiport until you should chose to modify them by updating your preferences in the same application.

Certiport occasionally allows other companies to offer our customers information about their products and services. If you do not wish to receive such offers, you may so indicate in the opt-out application. 

**Security of your Personal Information**  
Certiport strictly protects the security of your personal information and honors your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. 

**Protection of Children’s Personal Information**  
Parents or guardians: we want to help you guard your children’s privacy. We encourage you to talk to your children about safe and responsible use of their personal information while using the Internet.

**Use of Cookies**  
Certiport Web sites may utilize cookies as a mechanism for controlling access, content, and interactions within the site. However we do not track individuals’ use of the site. All information gathered through the use of cookies or access logs is used only in aggregate and is never traced to individual users.

**Changes to this Statement**  
Certiport will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also update the “last updated” date found at the bottom of the privacy statement.

**Contact Information**  
Should you wish to comment on this statement, or if you have other concerns regarding your personal information, please contact us by [e-mail](mailto:privacy@Certiport.com) or at (801) 492-1551.

Last updated: 17 August 2001
